A Guide to the Corbin Family Papers, 1794-1815
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, 1794-1815
Library of Virginia
24976
11 leaves and 53 pages
Corbin family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Leon M. Bazille, Elmont, Virginia, 28 October 1951.
Biographical Information
John Tayloe Corbin (1739-16 February 1794) served as a member of the House of Burgesses from King and Queen County, Virginia, from 1769 to 1774. He married Maria Waller (14 July 1752-16 September 1796) 16 February 1771, and they had seven chidren. One of their children, Richard Corbin (2 December 1771-10 June 1819), served as a member of the House of Delegates for Middlesex County, Virginia, in 1796, and for King and Queen County from 1798 to 1800. He was also a prominent landholder. Corbin married Rebecca Parke Farley (d. 20 April 1822) 15 November 1794 and they had six children. Richard Corbin's sister Martha Maria Corbin (b. 1784) married John B. Whiting; his sister Henrietta Matilda Corbin (b. 1792) married Madison Dillard; and his sister Elizabeth Tayloe Corbin married first Richard Henry Corbin, and second, Elliot Muse (1778-1818).
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1794-1815, of the Corbin family of King and Queen County, Virginia, consisting correspondence and papers of Maria Corbin and her son Richard Corbin and containing accounts, bonds, drafts, inventories, letters, propositions, and receipts. Correspondence discusses the estates of John Tayloe Corbin and Maria Corbin and the shares of these estates belonging to Richard Corbin and his siblings; the plantations of Laneville, Moss Neck, and White Hall; the buying and selling of slaves; accounts of money owed to and by Maria and Richard Corbin; crops; and Corbin family news. Proposal and inventory concern the renting of White Hall plantation from Richard Corbin by John Beverley Whiting. Drafts are from Whiting for payment of money to Thomas Muse, Elliot Muse, Peter Wiatt, and Richard Corbin. A letter, 17 January 1796, and a bond, 1 March 1809 are temporarily unavailable due to conservation needs.
Arrangement
chronological
Contents List
- Corbin Family Papers, 1794-1815
  - Letter, n.d., from an unknown correspondent, possibly Maria Corbin, to Samuel Harris., 1; 2 p., incomplete.
  - Letter, n.d., [Maria Corbin] to Richard [Corbin]., 2; 4 p., incomplete.
  - Letter, 1 September 1794, Maria Corbin, Laneville, [King and Queen County, Virginia], to Richard Corbin, Park Place, Williamsburg, [Virginia]., 3; 2 p.
  - Letter, 3 November 1794, Maria Corbin, Laneville, to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg., 4; 3 p.
  - , 3 December 1794, Maria Corbin to Richard Corbin., 5; 4 p.
  - Letter, 7 December 1794, George Turner to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg., 6; 2 p.
  - Letter, 17 March 1795, George Turner, Richmond, [Virginia], to [Richard Corbin]., 7; 2 p.
  - Letter, 17 March 1795, Maria Corbin, Laneville, to Richard [Corbin]., 8; 4 p.
  - Letter, 30 April 1795, George Turner, Fredericksburg, [Virginia], to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg., 9; 2 p.
  - Letter, 30 May 1795, George Turner, Laneville, to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg., 10; 2 p.
  - Letter, 17 January 1796, George Turner, Laneville, to Richard Corbin., 11; 4 p.
  - Letter, 6 August 1796, Richard Corbin to an unknown recipient., 12; 2 p.
  - Letter, 11 January 1797, Charles Young, attorney for Thomas Blane of York [County, Virginia?], to Maria Corbin, Laneville., 13; 1 leaf.
  - Letter, 7 September 1797, Daniel Turner, Moss Neck, [Caroline County, Virginia], to Richard Corbin, Laneville., 14; 3 p.
  - Draft, 20 February 1807, John B. Whiting on Richard Corbin for 169 p 4 s for the benefit of Captain Peter Wiatt., 15; 2 p.
  - Draft, 25 February 1807, John B. Whiting on Richard Corbin for $950 for the benefit of Thomas Muse., 16; 2 p.
  - Letter, 5 November 1807, John B. Whiting to Richard Corbin, Laneville, King and Queen County., 17; 1 leaf.
  - Receipt, 19 December 1807, John B. Whiting to Richard Corbin, Laneville, King and Queen County, for $1000 and three slaves., 18; 2 p.
  - Letter, 2[8] December 1807, John B. Whiting to Richard Corgin, Laneville, King and Queen County., 19; 1 leaf.
  - Proposition, 14 February 1808, to John B. Whiting for renting White Hall in Gloucester County, Virginia, from Richard Corbin. Attested by Read Watlington., 20; 3 p.
  - Inventory, 14 February [1808], of the property at White Hall delivered to John B. Whiting. Attested by REad Watlington., 21; 2 p.
  - Drafts, 2 April 1808, John B. Whiting on Richard Corbin for $2000 for the benefit of Elliott Muse., 22; 2 leaves.
  - Draft, 11 June 1808, John B. Whiting on Elliott Muse for $250 for the benefit of Richard Corbin., 23; 1 leaf.
  - Letter, 13 February 1809, John B. Whiting to Richard Corbin, Laneville., 24; 1 leaf.
  - Bond, 1 March 1809, John Beverley Whiting and Ralph Wormeley to Richard Corbin of Laneville., 25; 1 leaf.
  - Account, [November 1809], Richard Corbin in account with the estate of George Turner, deceased., 26; 2 p.
  - Letter, 6 November 1812, John B. Whiting to Richard Corbin, Laneville, King and Queen County., 27; 1 leaf.
  - Letter, 28 August 1813, John B. Whiting, Gloucester Court House, [Virginia], to [Richard Corbin]., 28; 2 p.
  - Letter, 28 March 1815, Richard Corbin, Laneville, to Madison Dillard, Rural Villa, Caroline County, [Virginia]., 29; 1 leaf.
  - Letter, 3 August 1815, Madison Dillard, Caroline [County], to Richard Corbin, Laneville., 30; 1 leaf.